<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="tip_heading">
        <item>Increase bright light exposure during the day</item>
        <item>Reduce blue light exposure in the evening</item>
        <item>Don’t consume caffeine late in the day</item>
        <item>Reduce irregular or long daytime naps</item>
        <item>Try to sleep and wake at consistent times</item>
        <item>Take a melatonin supplement</item>
        <item>Consider these other supplements</item>
        <item>Don’t drink alcohol</item>
        <item>Optimize your bedroom environment</item>
        <item>Set your bedroom temperature</item>
        <item>Don’t eat late in the evening</item>
        <item>Relax and clear your mind in the evening</item>
        <item>Take a relaxing bath or shower</item>
        <item>Get a comfortable bed, mattress, and pillow</item>
        <item>Exercise regularly — but not before bed</item>
        <item>Don’t drink any liquids before bed</item>
        <item>Don’t Smoke</item>
    </string-array>



    <string-array name="tip_description">
        <item>Our internal clocks are regulated by light exposure. Sunlight has the strongest
            effect, so try to take in daylight by getting outside or opening up windows or
            blinds to natural light. Getting a dose of daylight early in the day can help
            normalize your circadian rhythm. If natural light isn’t an option, you can talk
            with your doctor about using a light therapy box.
            \n
            In people with insomnia, daytime bright light exposure improved sleep quality and
            duration. It also reduced the time it took to fall asleep by 83%.
        </item>

        <item>This is due to its effect on your circadian rhythm, tricking your brain into
            thinking it’s still daytime. This reduces hormones like melatonin, which help you
            relax and get deep sleep.
            \n
            Wear glasses that block blue light.
            Download an app such as \"f.lux\" to block blue light on your laptop or computer.
            Install an app that blocks blue light on your smartphone. These are available for
            both iPhone and Android models.
            Stop watching TV and turn off any bright lights for 2 hours before heading to bed.
        </item>

        <item>Caffeine has numerous benefits and is consumed by 90% of the U.S. population.
            A single dose can enhance focus, energy, and sports performance.
            However, when consumed late in the day, caffeine stimulates your nervous system and
            may stop your body from naturally relaxing at night.
            \n
            In one study, consuming caffeine up to 6 hours before bed significantly worsened
            sleep quality.
            Caffeine can stay elevated in your blood for 6–8 hours. Therefore, drinking large
            amounts of coffee after 3–4 p.m. is not recommended, especially if you’re
            sensitive to caffeine or have trouble sleeping.
        </item>


        <item>While short power naps are beneficial, long or irregular napping during the day
            can negatively affect your sleep.
            Sleeping in the daytime can confuse your internal clock, meaning that you may
            struggle to sleep at night.
            \n
            In fact, in one study, participants ended up being sleepier during the day after
            taking daytime naps.
            Another study noted that napping for 30 minutes or less can enhance daytime
            brain function, longer naps can harm health and sleep quality.
        </item>

        <item>Your body’s circadian rhythm functions on a set loop, aligning itself with
            sunrise and sunset.
            Being consistent with your sleep and waking times can aid long-term sleep quality.
            \n
            One study noted that participants who had irregular sleeping patterns and went to
            bed late on the weekends reported poor sleep.
            Other studies have highlighted that irregular sleep patterns can alter your
            circadian rhythm and levels of melatonin, which signal your brain to sleep.
            \n
            If you struggle with sleep, try to get in the habit of waking up and going to bed
            at similar times. After several weeks, you may not even need an alarm.
        </item>

        <item>Melatonin is a key sleep hormone that tells your brain when it’s time to relax
            and head to bed.
            Melatonin supplements are an extremely popular sleep aid.
            Often used to treat insomnia, melatonin may be one of the easiest ways to fall
            asleep faster.
            \n
            In one study, taking 2 mg of melatonin before bed improved sleep quality and
            energy the next day and helped people fall asleep faster.
            In another study, half of the group fell asleep faster and had a 15% improvement
            in sleep quality.
            \n
            Additionally, no withdrawal effects were reported in either of the above studies.
            Melatonin is also useful when traveling and adjusting to a new time zone, as it
            helps your body’s circadian rhythm return to normal.
        </item>





        <item>Several supplements can induce relaxation and help you sleep, including:
            \n
        - Ginkgo biloba: A natural herb with many benefits, it may aid sleep, relaxation,
            and stress reduction, but the evidence is limited. Take 250 mg 30–60 minutes before
            bed.
            \n
        - Glycine: A few studies show that taking 3 grams of the amino acid glycine can improve
            sleep quality.
            \n
        - Valerian root: Several studies suggest that valerian can help you fall asleep and
            improve sleep quality. Take 500 mg before bed.
            \n
        - Magnesium: Responsible for over 600 reactions within your body, magnesium can
            improve relaxation and enhance sleep quality.
            \n
        - L-theanine: An amino acid, L-theanine can improve relaxation and sleep. Take 100–200
            mg before bed.
            \n
        - Lavender: A powerful herb with many health benefits, lavender can induce a calming
            and sedentary effect to improve sleep. Take 80–160 mg containing 25–46% linalool.
            \n
        Make sure to only try these supplements one at a time. While they’re not a magic bullet
            for sleep issues, they can be useful when combined with other natural sleeping
            strategies.
        </item>

        <item>Having a couple of drinks at night can negatively affect your sleep and hormones.
            Alcohol is known to cause or increase the symptoms of sleep apnea, snoring, and
            disrupted sleep patterns.
            It also alters nighttime melatonin production, which plays a key role in your
            body’s circadian rhythm.
            \n
            Another study found that alcohol consumption at night decreased the natural
            nighttime elevations in human growth hormone (HGH), which plays a role in your
            circadian rhythm and has many other key functions.
        </item>

        <item>Many people believe that the bedroom environment and its setup are key factors
            in getting a good night’s sleep.
            These factors include temperature, noise, external lights, and furniture
            arrangement.
            \n
            To optimize your bedroom environment, try to minimize external noise, light, and
            artificial lights from devices like alarm clocks. Make sure your bedroom is a
            quiet, relaxing, clean, and enjoyable place.
            Consider using room-darkening shades, earplugs, a fan, or other devices to create
            an environment that suits your needs.
        </item>

        <item>Body and bedroom temperature can also profoundly affect sleep quality.
            As you may have experienced during the summer or in hot locations, it can be very
            hard to get a good night’s sleep when it’s too warm.
            \n
            One study found that bedroom temperature affected sleep quality more than external
            noise.
            Around 70°F (20°C) seems to be a comfortable temperature for most people, although
            it depends on your preferences and habits.
        </item>

        <item>Eating late at night may negatively affect both sleep quality and the natural
            release of HGH and melatonin.
            That said, the quality and type of your late-night snack may play a role as well.
            In one study, a high-carb meal eaten 4 hours before bed helped people fall asleep
            faster.
            \n
            Interestingly, one study discovered that a low-carb diet also improved sleep,
            indicating that carbs aren\'t always necessary, especially if you’re used to a low-carb diet.
            \n
            Don\'t go to bed hungry or stuffed. In particular, avoid heavy or large meals
            within a couple of hours of bedtime. Your discomfort might keep you up.
        </item>

        <item>Many people have a pre-sleep routine that helps them relax.
            Relaxation techniques before bed have been shown to improve sleep quality and are
            another common technique used to treat insomnia.
            \n
            Strategies include listening to relaxing music, reading a book, taking a hot bath,
            meditating, deep breathing, and visualization. Try out different methods and find
            what works best for you.
        </item>


        <item>A relaxing bath or shower is another popular way to sleep better.
            Studies indicate that they can help improve overall sleep quality and help people
            — especially older adults — fall asleep faster.
            \n
            In one study, taking a hot bath 90 minutes before bed improved sleep quality and
            helped people get more deep sleep.
            Alternatively, if you don’t want to take a full bath at night, simply bathing your
            feet in hot water can help you relax and improve sleep.
        </item>

        <item>Apart from the relaxing environment, bed quality can also affect sleep.
            One study looked at the benefits of a new mattress for 28 days, revealing that it
            reduced back pain by 57%, shoulder pain by 60%, and back stiffness by 59%. It also
            improved sleep quality by 60%.
            \n
            The best mattress and bedding are extremely subjective. If you’re upgrading your
            bedding, base your choice on personal preference.
            It’s recommended that you upgrade your bedding at least every 5–8 years.
        </item>

        <item>Exercise is one of the best science-backed ways to improve your sleep and health.
            It can enhance all aspects of sleep and has been used to reduce symptoms of
            insomnia.
            One study in older adults determined that exercise nearly halved the amount of time
            it took to fall asleep and provided 41 more minutes of sleep at night.
            In people with severe insomnia, exercise offered more benefits than most drugs.
            /n
            Exercise reduced time to fall asleep by 55%, total night wakefulness by 30%, and
            anxiety by 15% while increasing total sleep time by 18%.
            Although daily exercise is key for a good night’s sleep, performing it too late
            in the day may cause sleep problems.
            This is due to the stimulatory effect of exercise, which increases alertness and
            hormones like epinephrine and adrenaline.
        </item>

        <item>Nocturia is the medical term for excessive urination during the night.
            It affects sleep quality and daytime energy.
            Drinking large amounts of liquids before bed can lead to similar symptoms, though
            some people are more sensitive than others.
            \n
            Although hydration is vital for your health, it’s wise to reduce your fluid intake
            in the late evening.
            Try to not drink any fluids for 1–2 hours before going to bed.
            You should also use the bathroom right before going to bed, as this may decrease
            your chances of waking up ate night.
        </item>

        <item>Exposure to smoke, including secondhand smoke, has been associated with a range
            of sleeping problems including difficulty falling asleep and fragmented sleep.
        </item>



    </string-array>
</resources>